Marco Furone Full-stack Developer

London, UK marco.job92@gmail.com M. 07576564916

Profile

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience, excellent **JAVA** development skills, good knowledge of OOP principles and experience with some well-known Frameworks.

Gained expertise as a **Full-stack** Developer working several times in a similar role using front-end technologies, in particular **JavaScript** / **Typescript**, **React** and **CSS**, exposing Web Services and working with Relational and NO-SQL Databases.

Often joined **Agile** teams, used micro-services architectures and functional programming languages.

Worked throughout his career in large and small organisations across a wide range of industries including banking, insurance, consulting, and the travel industry.

Experience

10/2022 to 11/2023

Go City London, UK

- Involved in the development of several new micro-services, both front-end and backend, to build new applications that have replaced legacy software in a technological transformation phase of the company resulting in annual savings of over £100k, performance improvements of up to 25% and more maintainable code.
- Designed software components, planned tickets, wrote technical specifications, working in an Agile team made of 10 people and collaborating on a daily basis with product managers, designers, stakeholders and software engineers, senior and junior.
- Being responsible for the delivery of the code to the production environment and being on-call on a monthly basis fixing production issues.

Technologies:

Java 17, Spring Boot, Kafka, Lombok, JUnit, Mockito, Gradle, PostregSQL Typescript, React, NextJs, Redux (Saga, Toolkit), CSS (styled-components), Jest, Cypress Kubernetes, Docker, yaml, Helm, Prometheus, Grafana, CircleCl, API Gateway MySQL and PostregSQL, Python and Airflow

06/2020 to 09/2022

3D INNOVATIONS London, UK

- Designed and developed an application (and its CMS) from scratch, which shows information and analysis about **Market Indexes**.
- Took business requirements and turned them into application functionalities, leading the entire development and delivery of the project using a BDD process.
- Developments and maintenance of a legacy flagship application.
 Moved this application to AWS and improved several heavy SQL queries that resulted in an overall load speed improvement of ~30%.

03/2019 to 01/2020

Credit Suisse London, UK

- Development from scratch of a Data-driven Web Application in a Bank environment, working full-stack with JavaScript (ES 6), an OOP language (JAVA) and a functional programming language (Clojure), using dynamic technologies to store and retrieve data (GraphQL and MongoDB), working with a Docker environment.
- Part of an Agile team interacting with technical and non-technical people (front-office).

01/2018 to 12/2018

ALLIANZ Milan, Italy

- Development, mainly with Java 8 using a TDD approach, of an Application for Document Management that allowed users to upload and view documents.
- Exposed Web Services to external applications and internal back-end components working with a **micro-services** architecture.
- Development of stand-alone applications for massive upload of documents.

01/2017 to 12/2017

HIGHWAY Milan, Italy

- Full-Stack Development of a **JAVA / Javascript** eCommerce (and its Management Application), working in a highly specialised Web Agency.
- Development of a small client application that consumed REST services using C#.
- Development of a Facebook Chatbot using NodeJS and a NO-SQL database.

07/2016 to 12/2016

DELOITTE DIGITAL Milan, Italy

• Front-end and Back-end development of a B2B eCommerce for an important client (MSC Cruise Company), working in an **Agile Scrum** large team.

05/2016 to 06/2016

GCI Milan, Italy

- Front-end (**AngularJS** 1.x, **Javascript**) and Back-End (**Java**, **Jax-RS**, **Hibernate**) development of a Management Web Application.
- Banking consultancy (SSM) for an important Italian Bank (*Intesa Sanpaolo*) working on a **Big Data** project.

www.timesheetevo.com

Developed a web-based SaaS Management Application on my own: *Timesheet Evo*. It is an independent Web Application for managing employee timesheets, expense notes and leave requests.

The website also contains its 'commercial' landing paging, although this is not a real commercial application and was developed entirely by me shortly after my graduation during my free time to explore new solutions and experiment with technologies.

Technologies used: Java, JavaScript, AngularJS 1.x, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SQL.

Website: http://www.timesheetevo.com

Sample user: timesheetevo@gmail.com; password: 123456

Web Portfolio: http://www.marcofurone.com

GitHub: https://github.com/MarcoJob92

Skills

Programming Languages:

Expert: Java

Proficient: JavaScript and Typescript

Prior experience: Clojure, NodeJS, C#, Python.

Java:

Spring boot (Core, Web, Data, Security), **Hibernate,** Junit, Mockito, Maven, Gradle, Lombok, JAX-RS, JAX-WS, Struts, Servlet, JSP, JSTL, JDBC, EJB, Hadoop (HIVE).

Front-end:

React (hooks), NextJS, Redux (Saga, Toolkit), Jest, Cypress, HTML5, CSS (Sass), npm JavaScript (ECMAScript 6), Typescript, Axios, Ajax, JQuery, Bootstrap.

Good knowledge of:

Kubernetes, **SQL** language, **MongoDB**, **XML** and **JSON** as data exchange formats, **micro-service** architecture, **MVC** and **ORM** Patterns, **REST** and **SOAP** Services, **GIT**, API Gateway.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science, March 2016.

University of Messina, Sicily, Italy.

Completion of two OOP courses during university: C++ and Java.

Thesis title: Design and implementation in java of a Client/Server system for the management of a library.

• **2-week .NET Framework Course**, April 2016.

Milan, Italy.

Technologies: C#, ASP .NET Framework, Entity Framework, SQL Server.